A Guide to the Blackwell Family Papers 1848-1937
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Blackwell Family Papers 1848-1937
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5764-b
This collection consists of ca. 12 shelf feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Mrs. Edward J. Jones (Lucy Blackwell Jones), Clifton Farm, Route #1, Warrenton, Virginia 22186. It was removed from storage at Clifton Farm and transferred to the University of Virginia Library where the Manuscripts Division accessioned it on February 19, 1974.
Scope and Content Information
The Blackwell Family Papers consist of correspondence, photographs and miscellany, of the interrelated Blackwell, Leavell, and Smith Families. By far the largest part of the collection is family correspondence among the Blackwells and Leavells during the years 1895-1923. Of particular interest are: the letters of Louise and Nancy Blackwell, who attended Randolph-Macon Woman's College, 1899-1905; the letters of Joseph M. Blackwell, who attended the U.S. Naval Academy, 1905-1911, and served in the Navy until his death in 1923; the letters of Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr., who attended the University of Virginia 1910?-1912; and the letters of Edwin and John Davenport Blackwell, who served in the U.S. Army during World War I. Students of medical history may find useful information in the Smith Family Papers and in the correspondence of Nannie Leavell Blackwell and her daughters Nancy and Agnes. The two daughters suffered severe hearing losses as a result of childhood illness. Agnes Blackwell's letters also contain much of interest about her career as an interior decorator in Bar Harbor, Maine.
As a whole, the collection will be of interest to social historians because it contains a substantial portion of an entire family's correspondence for an extended period of time. The letters document in detail the successes, failures, and tragedies of a prominent Fauquier County, Virginia, family.
On the other hand, readers will find few letters of the father, Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr., who was a faculty member of Bethel Military Academy, and relatively little information on the Academy itself.
The major family correspondents are Jonathan M. Leavell (b. 1824) and his wife Louisa M. Leavell (b. 1827), several of their children, Lizzie Newton Leavell (b. 1861), Byrd Leavell (b. ?), Nannie Fillmore (Leavell) "Mrs. Edwin S." Blackwell, (b. 1856) and the Blackwell children, Nancy, Louise "Mrs. Hugh" McClung, Agnes, Edwin S., Jr., Joseph M., and John Davenport.
In addition to the manuscript items, the collection included ca. 8 inches of sheet music, many printed items including books, newspapers, playbills, and ca. 30 daguerreotypes.
Arrangement
Except for the small collection of Smith Family Papers, which are grouped in one box, the collection of correspondence is arranged by author in one chronological series. Thus, the box containing the years 1904- 1905 holds all of the family correspondence of those years arranged in folders generally by individual correspondent. Miscellaneous correspondence to a family member from non-family members is included in the folder of the addressee except for the volumnious miscellaneous correspondence of Nannie Leavell Blackwell and Lizzie N. Leavell, which is separately foldered.
Contents List
- Blackwell Family Papers
  - John M. Leavell 1848-1895 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1866 (Box 1)
  - Charles R. Lake, R.E. Timberlake, G.R. Cannon, Jonathan R. Strother to Nancy Leavell[e] Blackwell 1874-1878 (Box 1)
  - Ella Jameson to Nancy Leavell[e] Blackwell ca. 1874-1879 (Box 1)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1874-1889 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1876 (Box 1)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1881 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1881 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1889 (Box 1)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1890 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1890 (Box 1)
  - W.G. Leavell 1890-1891 (Box 1)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1891 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1891 (Box 1)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr. 1891-1895 (Box 1)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1892 (Box 1)
  - Byrd Leavell 1892 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1892 (Box 1)
  - M.L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1892 (Box 1)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1893 (Box 1)
  - Byrd Leavell 1893 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1893 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1893 (Box 1)
  - Byrd Leavell 1893 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1894 (Box 1)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1894 (Box 1)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1894 (Box 1)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1894 (Box 2)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1894 (Box 2)
  - Byrd Leavell 1895 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1895 (Box 2)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1895 (Box 2)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1895 (Box 2)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1895 (Box 2)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1895 (Box 2)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1896 (Box 2)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1896 (Box 2)
  - George A. Huggins to Lizzie Leavell 1896 (Box 2)
  - Byrd Leavell 1896 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1896 (Box 2)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1896 (Box 2)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1896 (Box 2)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1896 (Box 2)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1897 (Box 3)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1897 (Box 3)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1897 (Box 3)
  - George A. Huggins to Lizzie Leavell 1897 (Box 3)
  - Byrd Leavell 1897 (Box 3)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1897 (Box 3)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1897 (Box 3)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1897 (Box 3)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1898 (Box 3)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1898 (Box 3)
  - George A. Huggins to Lizzie Leavell 1898 (Box 3)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1898 (Box 3)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1898 (Box 3)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1898 (Box 3)
  - Lucie Leavell 1898 (Box 3)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1898 (Box 3)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1898 (Box 3)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1899 (Box 4)
  - Louise Blackwell 1899 (Box 4)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1899 (Box 4)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1899 (Box 4)
  - George A. Huggins to Lizzie Leavell 1899 (Box 4)
  - Byrd Leavell 1899 (Box 4)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1899 (Box 4)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1899 (Box 4)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1899 (Box 4)
  - Louise Blackwell 1900 (Box 4)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1900 (Box 4)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1900 (Box 4)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell 1900 (Box 4)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1900 (Box 4)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1900 (Box 4)
  - Lucie Leavell 1900 (Box 4)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1900 (Box 4)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1900 (Box 4)
  - George A. Huggins to Lizzie Leavell 1900 (Box 4)
  - George A. Huggins to Lizzie Leavell 1900-1909 (Box 4)
  - Louise Blackwell 1901 (Box 5)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1901 (Box 5)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1901 (Box 5)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1901 (Box 5)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1901 (Box 5)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1902 (Box 5)
  - Louise Blackwell 1902 (Box 5)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1902 (Box 5)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr. 1902 (Box 5)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1902 (Box 5)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1902 (Box 5)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1903 (Box 5)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1903 (Box 5)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1903 (Box 5)
  - Louise Blackwell 1903 (Box 5)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1903 (Box 5)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1903 (Box 5)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell - Grade Reports 1903-1909 (Box 5)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1904 (Box 6)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1904 (Box 6)
  - Louise Blackwell 1904 (Box 6)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1904 (Box 6)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1904 (Box 6)
  - Byrd Leavell 1904-1905 (Box 6)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1904 (Box 6)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1905 (Box 6)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1905 (Box 6)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr. 1905 (Box 6)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1905 (Box 6)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1905 (Box 6)
  - Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1905 (Box 6)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1905 (Box 6)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1905 (Box 6)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1905 (Box 6)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1905 (Box 6)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1906 (Box 7)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Louise Blackwell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1906 (Box 7)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1906 (Box 7)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1906 (Box 7)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1906-1907 (Box 7)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1907 (Box 7)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1907 (Box 7)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1907 (Box 7)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1907 (Box 8)
  - Louise Blackwell 1907 (Box 8)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1907 Jan.-March (Box 8)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1907 April-Dec. (Box 8)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1907 (Box 8)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1907 (Box 8)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1907 (Box 8)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1907 (Box 8)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1907 (Box 8)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1908 (Box 8)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1908 (Box 8)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1908 (Box 8)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1908 (Box 9)
  - Louise Blackwell 1908 (Box 9)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1908 (Box 9)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1908 (Box 9)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1908 (Box 9)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1908 June-Sept. (Box 9)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1908 Oct.-Dec. (Box 9)
  - Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1908 (Box 10)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1908 (Box 10)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1908 (Box 10)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr. 1908-1909 (Box 10)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1909 (Box 10)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1909 (Box 10)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1909 (Box 10)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1909 (Box 10)
  - Louise Blackwell 1909 (Box 10)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1909 (Box 10)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1909 (Box 10)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1909 (Box 10)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1909 Jan.-April (Box 11)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1909 May-Dec. (Box 11)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1909 (Box 11)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1909 (Box 11)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1909 (Box 11)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1909 (Box 11)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1910 (Box 11)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1910 (Box 12)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1910 (Box 12)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1910 (Box 12)
  - Louise Blackwell 1910 (Box 12)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1910 (Box 12)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1910 (Box 12)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1910 (Box 12)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1910 Jan.-June (Box 12)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1910 July-Dec. (Box 13)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1910 (Box 13)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1910 (Box 13)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1910 (Box 13)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1910 (Box 13)
  - M. L. Waite to Lizzie Leavell 1910 (Box 13)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr. 1910-1911 (Box 13)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1911 (Box 13)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell 1911 Jan. -Sept. (Box 13)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1911 Oct.-Dec. (Box 14)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1911 (Box 14)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1911 (Box 14)
  - Louise Blackwell 1911 (Box 14)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1911 (Box 14)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1911 (Box 14)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1911 (Box 14)
  - Norman A. Buckley to Agnes Blackwell 1911 (Box 14)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1911 (Box 15)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1911 (Box 15)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1912 (Box 15)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1912 (Box 15)
  - Re: Death of E. S. Blackwell, Sr. 1912 Nov.-Dec. (Box 15)
  - Re: Death of E. S. Blackwell, Sr. 1912 Nov.-Dec. (Box 15)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1912 (Box 15)
  - Louise Blackwell 1912 (Box 16)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1912 (Box 16)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1912 (Box 16)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1912 (Box 16)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1912 (Box 16)
  - Byrd Leavell 1912 (Box 16)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1912 (Box 16)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1912 (Box 16)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1913 (Box 16)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1913 (Box 16)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1913 (Box 16)
  - Louise Blackwell 1913 (Box 16)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1913 (Box 16)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1913 (Box 17)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1913 (Box 17)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1913 (Box 17)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1913 (Box 17)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1913 (Box 17)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1914 (Box 17)
  - Edwin Blackwell, Jr. 1914 (Box 17)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1914 (Box 17)
  - Re: John Davenport Blackwell -Higher Education 1914 (Box 17)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1914 (Box 17)
  - Louise Blackwell 1914 (Box 17)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1914 (Box 18)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1914 (Box 18)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1914 (Box 18)
  - Byrd Leavell 1914 (Box 18)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1914 (Box 18)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1914 (Box 18)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1915 (Box 18)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1915 Jan.-June (Box 18)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. 1915 July-Dec. (Box 18)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1915 (Box 18)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1915 (Box 19)
  - Louise Blackwell 1915 (Box 19)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1915 (Box 19)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1915 (Box 19)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1915 (Box 19)
  - Byrd Leavell 1915 (Box 19)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1915 (Box 19)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1915 (Box 19)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1916 (Box 19)
  - Edwin S. Blackewll, Jr. 1916 (Box 19)
  - Re: Death of E. S. Blackwell, Sr. 1916 Feb. (Box 19)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Louise Blackwell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1916 (Box 20)
  - Byrd Leavell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1916 (Box 20)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1916 (Box 20)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1917 (Box 21)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1917 (Box 21)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1917 (Box 21)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1917 (Box 21)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1917 (Box 21)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1917 (Box 21)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1917 (Box 21)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1917 (Box 21)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1917 (Box 21)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1918 (Box 22)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1918 (Box 22)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1918 (Box 22)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1918 (Box 22)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1918 (Box 22)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1918 (Box 22)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1918 (Box 22)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1918 (Box 22)
  - Byrd Leavell 1918 (Box 22)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1918 (Box 22)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker 1918 (Box 22)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1919 (Box 23)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1919 (Box 23)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1919 (Box 23)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1919 (Box 23)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1919 (Box 23)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1919 (Box 23)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1919 (Box 23)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1919 (Box 23)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1919 (Box 23)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1920 (Box 23)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1920 (Box 23)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1920 (Box 23)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1920 (Box 24)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1920 (Box 24)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1920 (Box 24)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1920 (Box 24)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1920 (Box 24)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1920 (Box 24)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1921 (Box 24)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1921 (Box 24)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1921 (Box 24)
  - Louise Blackwell 1921-1937 (Box 24)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1921 (Box 24)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1921 (Box 24)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1921 (Box 24)
  - Norman A. Buckley 1921 (Box 24)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Byrd Leavell 1921 (Box 24)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1921 (Box 24)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1921 (Box 24)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1922 (Box 25)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1922 (Box 25)
  - Joseph Blackwell 1922 (Box 25)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1922-1924 (Box 25)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1922 (Box 25)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1922 (Box 25)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1922 (Box 25)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1922 (Box 25)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1923 (Box 25)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1923 (Box 25)
  - Re: Death of Joseph Blackwell 1923 (Box 25)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1923 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1923 (Box 26)
  - Byrd Leavell 1923 (Box 26)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1923 (Box 26)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1923 (Box 26)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1924 (Box 26)
  - Mrs. Joseph Blackwell 1924 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1924 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1924 (Box 26)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1924 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1925 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1925 (Box 26)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1925 (Box 26)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1926 (Box 26)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1926 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1926 (Box 26)
  - Byrd Leavell 1926 (Box 26)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1926 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1927 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1928 (Box 26)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1929 (Box 26)
  - John Davenport Blackwell 1929 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1929 (Box 26)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1930 (Box 26)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1930 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1930 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1930 (Box 26)
  - Agnes, Nancy Blackwell and Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1931 (Box 26)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1931 (Box 26)
  - Agnes and Nancy Blackwell 1932 (Box 27)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1932 (Box 27)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1932 (Box 27)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1932 (Box 27)
  - Byrd Leavell 1932-1935 (Box 27)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1933 (Box 27)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1933 (Box 27)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1933 (Box 27)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1933 (Box 27)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1934 (Box 27)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1934 (Box 27)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1934 (Box 27)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell 1934 (Box 27)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1934 (Box 27)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1935 (Box 28)
  - Nancy Blackwell 1935 (Box 28)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1935 (Box 28)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell 1935 (Box 28)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1936 (Box 28)
  - Agnes Blackwell 1937 (Box 28)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous 1937 (Box 28)
  - Agnes Blackwell n.d., frag. (Box 28)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. n.d., frag. (Box 28)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Sr. n.d. (Box 28)
  - John Davenport Blackwell n.d., frag. (Box 28)
  - Joseph Blackwell n.d., frag. (Box 28)
  - Louise Blackwell n.d., frag. (Box 28)
  - Nancy Blackwell n.d., frag. (Box 28)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell n.d., frag. (Box 29)
  - Nancy Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous n.d., frag. (Box 29)
  - Norman A. Buckley n.d. (Box 29)
  - Mrs. John M. Leavell n.d., frag. (Box 29)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell n.d., frag. (Box 29)
  - Clayton and Van Clief Ricker n.d., frag. (Box 29)
  - Unidentified correspondence (Box 29)
- Miscellaneous Papers
  - Agnes Blackwell - Composition, Drawing, Music Books n. d. (Box 30)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. - Notebook 1901-1902 (Box 30)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, Jr. - School notebooks 1911-1912 (Box 30)
  - Edwin S. Blackwell, S. - School notebooks 1873-1874 (Box 30)
  - Joseph Blackwell - School notebook ca. 1908 (Box 30)
  - Joseph Blackwell - School notebooks n. d. (Box 30)
  - Nancy Blackwell - School notebooks ca. 1890-1895 (Box 31)
  - Nancy Blackwell - School notebooks n. d. (Box 31)
  - W. Duffy - School notebook 1867 (Box 31)
  - Montague (?) - School notebook ca. 1875? (Box 31)
  - Unidentified notebook n. d. (Box 31)
  - John Davenport Blackwell - Grade Reports 1908-1911 (Box 31)
  - Joseph Blackwell - Grade Reports 1897-1911 (Box 31)
  - Louise Blackwell - Grade Reports 1901-1902 (Box 31)
  - Nancy Blackwell - Grade Reports 1901 - 1903 (Box 31)
  - E. S. Blackwell, Jr. - Miscellaneous Exams and Papers ca. 1908 (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous Mss and School Papers n. d. (Box 32)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Autograph Book 1873-1878 (Box 32)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Ledgers, Memo Books ca. 1908 - 1933 (Box 32)
  - John Minor Leavell - Justice of the Peace Records, Culpeper, Virginia 1851 - 1859 (Box 32)
  - Bethel (Va.) Methodist Episcopal Church Records 1901-1905 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Christmas Cards, Announcements n. d. (Box 33)
  - Agnes Blackwell - Christmas Cards and Miscellaneous Cards ca. 1880-1940 (Box 33)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous Christmas Cards 1933, 1935 (Box 33)
  - Lizzie N. Leavell - Miscellaneous Greeting Cards ca. 1900-1935 (Box 33)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Miscellaneous Invitations and Announcements ca. 1910-1931 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous Postcards n. d. (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous Leather Postcards ca. 1905-1908 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous Newsclippings n. d. (Box 34)
  - Benjamin Brown - Last Will and Testament 1752 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Theatre, Concert, Opera, Cinema Programs ca. 1900-1925 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Poetry n. d. (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscripts n. d. (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter n. d. (Box 35)
  - Oil Painting, Landscape n. d. (Box 35)
  - John Davenport Blackwell - Photographs ca. 1917 (Box 35)
  - Blackwell Family Photographs n. d. (Box 35)
  - Photographs - Huggins, Machen, Anderson, and Dandge n. d. (Box 35)
  - Bethel Military Academy Baseball Team Photo n. d. (Box 35)
  - Photograph - "Northern Belle" n. d. (Box 35)
  - Unidentified Photographs n. d. (Box 35)
  - John Davenport Blackwell - Miscellaneous 1905, 1926 (Box 36)
  - Agnes Blackwell - Car Insurances, Income Tax, etc. 1908-1913, 1929, 1938 (Box 36)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - MsS re Family Animals n. d. (Box 36)
  - Mr. And Mrs. E. s. Blackwell - Miscellaneous Contracts ca. 1915-1929 (Box 36)
  - Mrs. E. S. Blackwell - Insurance, Cemetery Care ca. 1919-1931 (Box 36)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Sunday School Record Book, Various Memo Books 1876-1919 (Box 36)
  - Nannie Leavell Blackwell - Ladies Aid Society Minutes ca. 1903 (Box 36)
  - E. S. Blackwell, Sr. - Memo Book ca. 1900 (Box 36)
  - Naval Academy Miscellany ca. 1900-1920 (Box 36)
  - Bethel Military Academy - Miscellany 1894-1910 (Box 36)
  - University of Virginia - Miscellany 1907, 1911-1912 (Box 36)
  - Warrenton Hunt Club 1927 (Box 36)
  - Maps 1904, 1917 (Box 36)
  - Broadsides - Miscellaneous ca. 1913, 1927 (Box 36)
  - Church Programs ca. 1923-1935 (Box 36)
  - Re: Family History n. d. (Box 36)
- Smith Family Papers
  - Smith Family Papers 1857-1859 (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers 1864-1869 (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers 1879-1889 (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers 1891-1899 (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers 1900-1907 (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers 1908-1909 (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers n. d. (Box 37)
  - Smith Family Papers n. d. (Box 37)
  - Dr. Thomas W. Smith - Medical Pamphlets n. d. (Box 37)
- Miscellaneous Items
  - University of Virginia Autograph Album 1892 (Box 37)